golden1.com 2004-12-06

# The Golden 1 Credit Union

|  |  | 

Privacy Statement

**Privacy Policy and Notice for The Golden 1 Credit Union and Golden 1 Financial Services, Inc.

Effective January 1, 2004

**

The Golden 1 and its affiliate, Golden 1 Financial Services, Inc. (G1FS), are committed to providing you with financial products and services to meet your needs and helping you reach your financial goals. Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information and ensuring the accuracy of such information is one of our top priorities. Neither The Golden 1 nor G1FS sell any of your personal information to nonaffiliated third parties, although we do disclose that information as provided below. While either The Golden 1 or G1FS may offer products or services on behalf of outside companies, The Golden 1 or G1FS controls the information used to make those offers. This privacy policy describes how The Golden 1 and G1FS collect and use your personal information, and how we maintain the confidentiality and accuracy of such information. This policy is provided pursuant to Title V of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (the Federal Privacy Act).

**Information that We Collect about You**  
We collect and maintain your information to serve you and to administer your business relationship with The Golden 1 and G1FS. Specifically, we collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:   

* Information we receive from you on applications or other forms received verbally, electronically, or in writing, including information such as Social Security numbers, addresses, e-mail addresses, income, assets, and debt;   

* Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency, including information we receive from an outside company such as a credit bureau providing your credit history, credit score, or employment verification;   

* Information created as a result of your being a customer of G1FS, or your being a Golden 1 member or nonmember joint owner on a deposit or loan account, such as account numbers, personal identification numbers (PIN), and passwords;   

* Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others, including information about your transactions or experiences, such as insurance contracts issued to you, brokerage accounts, loan or deposit balance histories;   

* Information received from other sources to verify the information that you provide on an application. This may be obtained from your current or past employers, or other institutions where you have conducted financial transactions in the past. 

**Information Use and Disclosure within The Golden 1 and G1FS**  
We may disclose all of the information that we collect, as described above, within The Golden 1 or G1FS for a variety of reasons, including the following:   

* To protect the security of your account or business relationship. For example, we use your personal information for identification purposes, to prevent unauthorized persons from accessing your accounts or records with us.   

* To conduct our business in a safe and sound manner. For example, we use information gathered in loan applications to ensure that we underwrite loans in a prudent manner consistent with the requirements of credit union regulations.   

* To satisfy legal requirements. For example, we use your Social Security number for federal income tax reporting purposes.   

* To help us best serve your needs, services may be offered by The Golden 1 or G1FS; however, your nonpublic personal information will always remain in the control of The Golden 1 or G1FS and will not be shared except as permitted by law. For example, G1FS offers uninsured investment products through a joint marketing arrangement administered by a provider of securities and broker/dealer services, but your information is not shared with the third party until you have indicated a desire to receive the services being offered through a variety of delivery channels. 

**Information Use and Disclosure with Nonaffiliated Third Parties or Affiliates**  
When it comes to The Golden 1 or G1FS sharing its information with an outside party, we do so only as permitted or required by law, and for specific purposes to provide you products and services that you’ve requested or already have with us. We may disclose all of the information that we collect, as previously described. We share this information as needed to provide those products and services and to provide a good member experience. We may disclose nonpublic personal information about you to affiliates and to nonaffiliated third parties as permitted by law, including the following:  

* Financial service providers, such as companies that service your loan, provide you an insurance or securities product or relationship, mortgage insurers or payment processors, mortgage bankers, securities brokers/dealers, and insurance agents;  

* Non-financial companies, such as companies that perform services on our behalf, for example, check printers, data processing companies, companies that prepare and mail account statements or notices, and companies that help us market our own products and services to you;   

* Other companies, such as independent contractors, including technical system consultants who program the software that helps us administer our products or market our products to you. 

****Information Disclosed to Outside Parties Who Are Service Providers and Financial Institutions with Whom We Have Joint Marketing Agreements****  
We may disclose all of the information we collect from members, as previously described, to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. For example, through a joint marketing arrangement, G1FS offers brokerage and securities services from another financial provider. 

**Information Disclosed to Outside Parties in Other Situations**  
Either The Golden 1 or G1FS might disclose member information to government agencies, consumer-reporting agencies, and other outside parties as permitted or required by the Federal Privacy Act and other applicable laws. These disclosures are made for specific, limited purposes. For example:   

* To verify individuals’ identities (reducing fraud and identity theft);   

* To meet member/customer service expectations (connecting to automated teller machine (ATM) networks for ATM Card access, and processing an application for insurance);  

* To verify information for prompt credit approvals (meeting members’ immediate financial needs);   

* To make certain information a matter of public record (recording mortgages to let prospective buyers, title insurers, and others know about property liens);   

* To comply as required with subpoenas, court orders, and legal reporting requirements, such as interest reporting to the Internal Revenue Service;   

* To relate our experience with you to credit reporting agencies and similar organizations, such as ChexSystems;   

* To comply with your written consent, including when you give someone power of attorney or other authorization to act on your behalf;   

* To act as an agent or broker of insurance or complete some other routine business transactions, such as selling traveler’s checks;   

* To process a proposed or actual transfer of accounts or line of business to another company;   

* To protect your accounts or business records against fraud and unauthorized transactions, to resolve member/customer disputes and, as necessary, to our regulators, attorneys, accountants, and auditors. 

In no event will we share any account number or any access code to any of your Golden 1 or G1FS accounts or business records with anyone, except as permitted by law.  
**  
Disclosure of Information about Former Members**  
It is generally unnecessary for us to disclose information about former members or customers of The Golden 1 or G1FS to others that have a relationship with us; however, to the extent we do disclose information, we will adhere to the same policies as previously described.

**How We Protect Your Information**  
We restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. Our employees are trained in the importance of maintaining confidentiality and member/customer privacy. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to guard your nonpublic personal information.

**Special Note**  
This privacy policy also applies to our online services. For a complete description of this privacy policy and other applicable online policies, visit our Web site at **golden1.com**. You may also make changes to your personal information related to your Golden 1 account by accessing “Member Services” within Golden 1 Online. You must be enrolled in Golden 1 Online to make changes to your account online.   

**Future Changes**  
This notice updates and replaces any previous notices you may have received from us about the collection, use, and protection of member/customer information. We may change this privacy notice at any time and if we do, we will notify you either by e-mail or by U.S. mail, depending on your relationship with The Golden 1. 

**Additional Rights**  
Some states may provide additional privacy protections under existing or future state laws. We are committed to complying with applicable law when we share member/customer information. 

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions regarding this privacy notice, please contact our Member Service Call Center at **(916) 732-2900** or **1-877-GOLDEN 1** from outside the Sacramento area.

|   
---|---|---|---
